qmiles.com 2019-05-30

# Privacy notice | Qatar Airways

**6.1 When you interact with Qatar Airways (online or offline)**

**(a) For answering your questions or responding to your complaints or requests  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

If you get in touch with us in person, through our Reservations and Ticketing Offices, our Qatar Airways Contact Centres, our IATA Travel Agents or Qatar Holidays, airport check in, Qatar Airways lounges, by email, by telephone, in writing or through our customer care services pages, through social media, on board or by your authorized representative for the purposes of the relevant enquiry, your Personal Data is collected only to the extent necessary to reply to and answer your question or to respond to your complaints or requests (e.g. to assist you in processing a transaction or to provide technical assistance).   

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on the performance of our passenger transport contract with you or in our legitimate business interests in providing customer care to you based on your request.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

We may use your Personal Data including special categories of Personal Data; for example full name, seat number, PNR number, contact details, ticket number, frequent flyer number, email address, country of primary residence, gender, flight number, date of travel, origin, destination, booking class, baggage information, travel date, type of passenger, special meal requests, special requests such as wheelchair assistance, when requested your health information to assess your fitness to travel, your correspondence with Qatar Airways about your question and all other Personal Data necessary to answer your question. We may monitor or record your phone conversations for training and customer service purposes.   

**(b) If you open a Qatar Airways account with us, to manage the account and to ensure confidentiality and security of your transactions and purchases  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

When you choose to register, create or modify an online or in-app account with us, including your Qatar Airways Privilege Club account or Qbiz account, you need to provide Personal Data so that we can create an account for you. Using this data allows us to manage your account, keep you updated about your account activity and to make sure that all your purchases and transactions are secure and confidential.   

In order to administer the Privilege Club programme, Qatar Airways may:  

(a) supply your Personal Data to Qatar Airways group companies, marketing partners, other airlines including oneworld airlines, agents, contractors, immigration, security and customs authorities;  

(b) transfer your personal data to other jurisdictions that may offer less protection of personal data than that provided in your own jurisdiction; and  

(c) process special categories of your Personal Data (such as data revealing a medical condition or religious belief) only where necessary to meet your special needs and requirements.  

Please refer to the Qatar Airways Privilege Club terms and conditions for details on how your personal data is collected and processed by our Privilege Club.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We process your Personal Data in the performance of the contract between you and Qatar Airways as (i) a website user, (ii) passenger travelling on Qatar Airways, (iii) a Privilege Club main member, family member or guest or (iv) a Member of Qbiz.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, 

(i) for your Qatar Airways basic account, we process your name, email address, title, telephone number, gender and date of birth, address, any other information you have added to your account, login data, display name, role, the details of your purchases and transactions and payment details.  

(ii) for your Privilege Club account, we process your name, email address, title, telephone number, gender and date of birth, address (current and permanent), passport data, nationality, FFP account number, tier information, language, travel history, any other information you have added to your account, login data, display name, role, and the details of your transactions and payment details. Where you have nominated family members you wish to enrol in the Privilege Club as a Main Member (as defined in the Privilege Club Terms and Conditions) or use Benefits for any Guest (as defined in the Privilege Club Terms and Conditions), we process their name, email address, title, telephone number, gender and date of birth, address, passport data, and any other information you have added to your account.  

(iii) for your Qbiz account, we process your name, email address, title, telephone number, gender and date of birth, address, any other information you have added to your account, login data, display name, role, the details of your transactions and payment details.  

**(c) To allow you to connect with us via social media  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

Qatar Airways is active on social media platforms including Facebook, Twitter, Google Plus, Flickr, Tumblr, Snapchat, LinkedIn, YouTube, Pinterest, VK, Sina, Weibo, WeChat and Instagram. When you contact us via social media, we will use Personal Data you supply in order to answer your questions and to respond to your messages.  

Your access and use of any social media platforms is governed by their own terms of use and privacy and cookie policies.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

Where you are a subscriber to the social media platforms and have given us your consent to our use of marketing cookies, we will provide you with relevant marketing when you use those platforms. If you wish to revoke your consent for the use of marketing cookies by Qatar Airways, you can change your cookie settings on our Website or Mobile Apps.  

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

Depending on the communication channel you have chosen to connect with us, we will use Personal Data you supply which may include your (user) name, address, email address, gender and the other Personal Data you have included in your message. In addition, when you click one of the buttons displayed such as “Like”, “Share” or retweet on our Website or Mobile Apps, the relevant social media platform might place cookies on your device. To read more about cookies, please read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.qatarairways.com/en/legal/cookie-policy.html).  

Any information which you choose to voluntarily post to our interactive forum, is by nature made publicly available to other users who have access to that portion of our Website. We encourage you not to share your Personal Data and we are not responsible for any information you choose to provide in such forums. Any disclosures you make are at your own risk.   

**(d) For the development and improvement of our products and/or services  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

It’s important for us to continue to provide you with our award winning services and uphold the Qatar Airways brand. In order to achieve this, we use your Personal Data so that we can assess, analyse and improve our services to you.   

For this purpose, we keep track of how often you read our newsletters, visit our Website and/or Mobile Apps, which pages you click on and what services you purchase through our Website or Mobile Apps.   

We also regularly use surveys to find out whether you are satisfied with our service. These surveys are conducted through our Website or Mobile Apps. We use your responses to surveys for quality assessments and to improve your customer experience.   

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on the performance of our passenger transport contract with you or in our legitimate business interests in enhancing our services to you.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, we use your contact details such as your address, email address, name, date of birth, payment and credit information, and any correspondence with us. In addition, we use the Personal Data you entered into the Website and/or Mobile Apps or based on the functionalities of the Website and/or Mobile Apps and the technical data from your device such as its IP-address, the pages you visited on our Websites or Apps, your click-through and surf behaviour and the length of your session.  

If you choose to participate in our surveys, we can ask you to provide us with Personal Data, such as age group, gender and preferences in terms of choice of destination. We can also use the Personal Data that you have provided in the survey for this purpose.  

**6.2 For the assessment and acceptance of a customer when travelling with us or using our ancillary services    
**

**(i) What does this mean?  **  

When you contact Qatar Airways, your Personal Data will be processed for assessment and acceptance purposes. This includes, confirming and verifying your identity or that of your authorised representative(s), verifying your identity at the security checkpoint and confirming your Personal Data at the check-in (i.e. at our counters or at self-check-in kiosks), during boarding or disembarkation, (i.e. security screening, baggage screening and flight transfers) and accessing Qatar Airways lounges, oneworld lounges or third party lounges or other ancillary services.

Qatar Airways will also process your Personal Data for other administrative and regulatory purposes such as due diligence and transportation security screening against publicly available government and/or law enforcement agency sanctions lists.   

Qatar Airways may also use and disclose your Personal Data to persons who have been validly identified as being you or your authorised representative(s) pursuant to our then-current security procedures, for the purpose of the relevant transaction or enquiry. In particular, each of the passengers who are grouped under the same booking reference (or Passenger Name Record (“ **PNR** ”) number shall be deemed to be authorised representatives of each of the other passengers under the same booking reference number.  

Where you have requested carriage of an unaccompanied child we will process your Personal Data for administrative purposes in order to facilitate the booking and safe travel of the child.   

Where you request medical clearance or conditional acceptance to assess your fitness to travel prior to your flight, you will be required to consent to and authorize the attending doctor to disclose necessary medical information to Qatar Airways and its commissioned medical advisors. This information will be solely used for the purpose of determining your fitness to fly on your booked flights.   

We will send you reminders about incomplete bookings and customer services emails to facilitate your booking completion and to identify any operational issues that prevented you from completing the transaction and/or offer assistance in a similar way.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on your request to enter into a passenger transport contract with us and pursuant to applicable legal obligations and regulatory requirements.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, we may process your contact details such as your postal address and email address, travel documents, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and credit information, meal preference, baggage details, health details and details of your correspondence with us. We will also process the Personal Data of those passengers travelling under the same booking reference number with you in a similar manner.   

**(iv) Automated decision-making**  

We use automated fraud detection algorithms to screen your online or telephone purchases in order to prevent fraudulent transactions.  

**6.3 For the performance of a contract  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

When you travel with us or request ancillary services offered through our Website, we process your Personal Data for administrative purposes such as:  

(a) facilitating your bookings and travel arrangements including transfers and stop overs;  

(b) administering our Privilege Club or Qbiz Programme;  

(c) administering our Al Maha Meet and Greet Services or services provided by Qatar Aviation Services such as ground handling, baggage services, travel and tours;   

(d) facilitating access to our Qatar Airways lounges, oneworld lounges or third party lounges;  

(e) administering city tours and activities, ground transportation services to your hotel or back to the airport, hotel bookings, travel insurance, car rentals or other ancillary services that you have requested through us, other Qatar Airways group companies or our third party service providers; and  

(f) facilitating your booking of duty free purchases online or duty free transactions at airport duty free shops or on board and transfer of purchased goods to the boarding and disembarkation gates.  

When you use airports, we process your Personal Data for administrative purposes such as to conduct security transportation identification and screening requirements required by those airports and imposed on airlines.   

We also use your Personal Data in order to deliver products or services that we have agreed to provide to you, such as in-flight catering, baggage handling, check-in and boarding. As part of our service to you, we provide you with flight alert and status messages through our Mobile Apps and SMS, service or informational emails, facilitate web and self-check-in kiosks, baggage notifications, and registering for our Privilege Club programme.  

We may offer an upgrade of your cabin before your flight via email.  

By using our services, our Website or Mobile Apps and by providing any Personal Data to us, you agree to your Personal Data being sent to and processed in countries outside of your country of residence, and for individuals resident in the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "), this includes transfers outside of the EEA. Some of these countries may not have data protection laws that provide an equivalent level of data protection as the laws in your country of residence. Please refer to Clause 8 of this Privacy Notice for more details.  

When you make a booking, you will be provided with a booking reference number. Disclosing your booking reference number with your surname to other persons or your travel agent will allow them to access your booking details through our system.   

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on our passenger transport contract with you and any other contracts that you have with the Qatar Airways group of companies or our third party service providers (where applicable). We will also process your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interests in offering a wide variety of ancillary services to you to enhance your travel experience. If you provide Personal Data on behalf of someone else (e.g., making a booking on behalf of an adult or a child), you enter into a passenger transport contract or other contract on behalf of that child or adult. 

**(ii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

We process the passenger’s contact details such as address and email address, personal details such as name and date of birth, payment and credit information, order history and other data stored in our customer, supplier and business partner database in relation to the passenger transport contract with you and any other contracts you have entered into with any entity of the Qatar Airways group of companies.  

**6.4 For organisational analysis and development, internal management, organisation reporting, and acquisition and divestitures**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

We process your Personal Data to help us analyse the performance and organisation of our business, including our management reporting and analysis.   

We also process your Personal Data to assist with internal management. Examples of this include providing central processing facilities in order to work more efficiently, conducting audits and investigations, implementing business controls and managing and using customer, supplier and business partner directories.   

We also process your Personal Data for finance and accounting, archiving and insurance purposes, legal and business consulting and in the context of dispute resolution.  

We use aggregated personal data to create management reports and to analyse Qatar Airways' business. We conduct customer, supplier and business partner surveys to learn more about your views and opinions in preparation for our management reporting. We also use your Personal Data for management reporting purposes in the context of mergers, acquisitions and divestitures and in order to manage such transactions. To ensure the security of your Personal Data, our analysis reporting is aggregated and anonymized and we require our employees, suppliers and partners to maintain confidentiality in accordance with applicable data protection laws.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on the performance of our passenger transport contract with you or in our legitimate business interests in maintaining the expected service levels to you.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and credit information, payment and order history, correspondence with Qatar Airways, data generated during the performance of the agreement between you and Qatar Airways, correspondence with Qatar Airways and the information you provide when responding to our surveys.  

**6.5 For compliance with law and to monitor and investigate compliance  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

Qatar Airways needs to comply with certain legal obligations and monitors it’s Website, Mobile Apps and IT systems to check compliance with Qatar Airways’ internal policies and regulations. During monitoring activities, your Personal Data can be accessed and viewed by Qatar Airways IT systems personnel or by third party regulators or government authorities.   

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on:  

(a) our legitimate business interests in maintaining adherence to our company policies and the standards which we uphold for our employees, suppliers and partners; and  

(b) our legal obligation to comply with laws and regulations which are applicable to the airline industry or to specific geographic locations. Please refer to our [Conditions of Carriage](https://www.qatarairways.com/en/legal/conditions-of-carriage.html) for further details.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, any Personal Data that is stored on Qatar Airways' IT systems can be accessed and viewed by Qatar Airways IT systems personnel or by third party regulators or government authorities for compliance purposes. The Personal Data that is accessed and viewed will not be stored for compliance purposes, unless we need them to further investigate potential non-compliant behaviour or in the course of legal proceedings.   

**6.6 In the event of an emergency  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

In the event of an emergency, Qatar Airways will be required to provide emergency response services and share your Personal Data and that of your emergency contact, with our oneworld alliance partners and emergency responses providers and authorities.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on the performance of our passenger transport contract with you, the protection of your vital interests and our legal obligation to comply with the applicable laws.  

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

For this purpose, we process your name, address, telephone number, gender, nationality, passport number and the Personal Data of the emergency contact that you named while making your booking.  

**6.7 Your choices  
**

**(a) If you participate in Contests, to manage your participation  
**

**(i) What does this mean?**  

If you give us your consent to do so, we can send you emails with invitations to participate in prize contests, events, competitions and/or games of chance (collectively “Contests”). If you choose to participate in any Contest, we need your Personal Data to allow you to participate, to administer the Contest, where you are a winner to inform you of this, to process the delivery of and distribution of the prizes and to measure the response to Contests.  

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will process your Personal Data based on the terms and conditions of the Contest. If you decline to provide this information, we will not be able to register or enter you into the relevant Contest or award you a prize if you have been successful.   

**(iii) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

Where we are the organiser or sponsor of the Contest, we process your name, address, email address, passport copy, your country of residence, proof of residence, age verification documentation, personal identification documentation, signature and your entries in the Contest. Please refer to the terms and conditions of the relevant Contest for specific details of the Personal Data processed. In accordance with the terms and conditions of the relevant Contest we may also share your Personal Data with third party sponsors of prizes in order to administer the prizes to you.  

**(b) Only if you subscribe to our mailing list, for sending you relevant information about Qatar Airways  **  

**(i) What does this mean?**  

We will occasionally inform you about our special offers, news and new products and may invite you to participate in Contests via the email address you provide us. You will only receive our newsletters if you subscribe to this mailing list.   

**(ii) What are our legal grounds for doing this?  **  

We will ask for your consent to send you personalised newsletters.   

**(iv) Which Personal Data do we use for this purpose?**  

We process your name and email address, your preferences and interests, (including those that you have actively shared with us, but also those inferred through your registered interactions with Qatar Airways Websites and Mobile Apps), (please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.qatarairways.com/en/legal/cookie-policy.html) for more information), shopping history (both online if you link your purchases to your profile, and offline when making an offline purchase), and the links you click on in our emails.
